{
    "id": "3639dada57b64e52a4659780d7a93101",
    "title": "Reported Speech Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The girl said that she ............................... unwell.",
            "description": "After a past reporting verb, we normally use a past tense in the reported speech. ",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "has been",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "b382c219774a40d78608cb2bd98e9eef"
        },
        {
            "question": "He said that his master ............................... his dinner.",
            "description": "After a past reporting verb, we normally use a past tense in the reported speech. ",
            "answers": [
                "is having",
                "was having",
                "has been having"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "99c005014b614334a48224a3790a45ca"
        },
        {
            "question": "The boy said that the horse .............................. in the night.",
            "description": "Simple past in the direct speech becomes past perfect in the indirect speech. ",
            "answers": [
                "has died",
                "died",
                "had died"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "ad1ee0b234474d3cbeac1fd21fd4540a"
        },
        {
            "question": "She told me that she ............................. trust me.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "doesn't",
                "didn't",
                "hasn't",
                "hadn't"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "da214487a9ed427798c478b3e5ccf148"
        },
        {
            "question": "He ........................ that he is glad to be here this evening.",
            "description": "We use a present tense in the reported speech only when the reporting verb is in the present tense. ",
            "answers": [
                "says",
                "said",
                "has said",
                "had said"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "8356feb24c2e45209f1ffc902606b05e"
        },
        {
            "question": "The stranger asked where ............................",
            "description": "Do is not used in reported questions. ",
            "answers": [
                "do I live",
                "did I live",
                "I lived"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "ae196de2923f4edba69d0a8604f5b6f0"
        },
        {
            "question": "My mother asked me whether I ..................................... a man like him.",
            "description": "Will in the direct speech becomes would in the indirect speech. ",
            "answers": [
                "will trust",
                "would trust",
                "trust"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "4d022a1f27b24d4a88d6fb01d9c13d88"
        },
        {
            "question": "The visitor requested the girl ............................ a glass of water.",
            "description": "We use to-infinitives to report commands, orders, requests etc. ",
            "answers": [
                "that bring",
                "to bring",
                "bring"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "3f272a5a15874438a6b9950fba7a9dc2"
        },
        {
            "question": "The mother wrote that she ............................... and longing for her son's return.",
            "description": "Present tenses in the direct speech become corresponding past tenses in the indirect speech. ",
            "answers": [
                "is waiting",
                "waited",
                "was waiting",
                "will wait"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "e4b323c6c94c496abc97c495e982a073"
        },
        {
            "question": "I told him that I ............................... his friend for months.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "did not see",
                "have not seen",
                "had not seen"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "337d2c13c8864849b019ba9cf3b400ab"
        },
        {
            "question": "He asked me ................................",
            "description": "In reported questions we do not use do. does or did. ",
            "answers": [
                "what did I want",
                "what I wanted",
                "what I want"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "012d173930b041ed83a871375c356171"
        },
        {
            "question": "The speaker said that it ......................... him great pleasure to be there that evening.",
            "description": "Present tenses in the direct speech become corresponding past tenses in the indirect speech. ",
            "answers": [
                "gives",
                "gave",
                "had given",
                "has given"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "38fdda1ac59b41cf805f13f4bfa5541a"
        }
    ]
}